mycarmex.com 2015-09-13

# Privacy Policy | Carmex : My Carmex

We at Carma Laboratories, Inc. (“Carma”) care about your privacy. We want to explain in detail our policies and procedures which we have adopted in order to protect your privacy while using our site, mycarmex.com. We want you to feel confident about how we handle personal information (your name, address, telephone number, credit card number, and email address), which you may have shared with us and to understand that this information is used to offer you the best possible products, services, and experiences to provide you with requested information, to enter contests/sweepstakes, and participate in promotions/postings or receive samples.

Below is a summary of our privacy policy, but please do take the time to read the policy in detail.

  * In the ordinary course of collecting personal information, we will not share any of your personal information with outside parties, except as needed for administrative reasons or as part of a corporate transaction (e.g., if Carma merges with another entity), or unless you explicitly agree to share your information with outside parties in order to receive information about such party’s products and/or services, participate in research, consumer trials, or other programs sponsored by or affiliated with Carma. We will use your personal information to fulfill your requests and to serve you better.
  * We will only send you information or products you have asked to receive [or according to your preferences]. Of course, we will honor your opt-out requests.
  * We do use cookies and web beacons to help us understand how users are using the website and to provide better functionality, as well as offering you personalized content.
  * We continue to adopt careful and secure procedures to protect any and all of your personal information. Special care is taken to protect any credit card data you provide when you shop online.
  * We reserve the right to use or disclose your personal information in certain circumstances, such as to satisfy a legal request or to protect our property.

## Changes in Our Policy

While we do not anticipate a need to change this privacy policy very often, we reserve the right to change or replace this policy at our discretion. We invite you to visit this Privacy Policy area often to ensure you are aware of any changes or updates to this Policy. Any changes we make will apply to all information we hold, even if the information was collected under a different policy.

## Consent to This Privacy Policy

By using our site, you consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with any terms of this Policy, please do not submit any personal information or use this site. If you choose not to submit any personal information, you may be denied access to particular areas of the website and/or from entering sweepstakes/contests, requesting samples, or sending us an email.

## Personal Information Collected and How We Use That Information

We collect personal information from you (i.e., name, address, phone number, email address, activity information, interests and the like) when you voluntarily provide it to us. Depending on the reason the information was provided, we may use the information to communicate with you about our products, services, promotions, and to provide information you have requested. We may also use it to make improvements to our products or services. You may be prompted to submit personal information in order to:

  * Register for a sweepstakes, contests or other promotions,
  * Register an account on our website,
  * Receive coupons through our website,
  * To join a club thru our website,
  * Participate in surveys and/or a consumer research committee,
  * Receive samples,
  * Receive emails with news and updates, and/or responses to your questions, comments or concerns,
  * Receive a newsletter or other material from us, and/or
  * Receive information about other Carma products.

Participation in any of these aforementioned activities (and therefore the provision of personal information) is completely voluntary. We will not send anyone any newsletter or email communications, unless you have asked to receive communications. We offer our customers the ability to opt out of receiving emails from Carma at any time by notifying us by email, or by following a link included at the bottom of our email communications.

## How We Use Cookies and Web Beacons

A cookie is a data file that is placed on your computer while you are visiting the website. These data files allow us to remember vital information that will enhance your experience and make the site more efficient, useful and make your visit as easy as possible. Information that may be kept track of would be IP address, type of browser, operating system, and pages viewed by the user on our site and other sites visited prior to ours. Cookies can be used to help prevent children from entering areas of the site that are intended for adults or teens.

Almost all browsers accept cookies automatically and the system can notify you when a cookie is being sent. You will have to refer to your browser help menu to learn how to disable cookies. Please keep in mind that if you disable cookies, you may not be able to access some of the features on our site.

Web beacons (known as one pixel GIF) are small pieces of computer code which allow us to count how many people visit our site or certain pages on the site or open an email. It allows us to better customize the website in order to personalize it and improve your experience while visiting. Cookies and web beacons do not collect or contain personal information like your name or your email address.

## Information Sharing

As mentioned earlier, at certain times we may share your personal information with other parties. The security of your personal information is a priority to us. We also may share this personal information with parties who provide services on our behalf. They will only be allowed to use information that directly applies to the service(s) they provide for us, and only for the purpose of providing the service(s). When we use these third parties we require them to protect your information just as we have done.

If we are asked to disclose any of the personal information to law enforcement agencies or if we are required by law, subpoena, court order or government entity, we must comply. We may also have to disclose personal information to conduct an investigation if legal action is brought against someone violating the use of this site. We also may share your information with companies assisting in fraud protection or investigation.

In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these business transfers, customer information, including personally identifiable information, is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if our site, Carma or substantially all of our assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, customer information, including personally identifiable information, would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of our site, Carma or any of our assets may continue to use your personally identifiable information as set forth in this policy.

## Public Forum

Any information you submit in a public forum (e.g., a post in a user forum on the site, a blog, chat room, or social network) can be read, collected, or used by us and others, and could be used to personalize your experience. You are responsible for the information you choose to submit in these instances. Such user-posted material is not subject to this Privacy Policy.

## Purchase of Products

Carmex® branded merchandise can be purchased through the Zazzle web store found at [zazzle.com/mycarmex](http://zazzle.com/mycarmex). The Zazzle Terms of Use found at that site govern your transaction, and Carma is not liable or otherwise responsible for any transaction or acts or omissions related to such transaction. Carma does not collect credit card information from users.

## Security Measures

We use a variety of current technologies and processes for protection of our customer data. We maintain a private database on our web server for the storage of all information collected through our site. It is our practice to use encryption whenever we receive or transmit sensitive data. (We use encryption technology to ensure the secure transmission of any personal information you provide while using our site. All transactions at our site are conducted using 128-bit Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption. You can easily determine when you’re sending data securely by looking at the web address (URL) in your browser window: the first few letters will change from “http” to “https” when you are transmitting information protected by SSL encryption. The “s” in “https” stands for “secure.”)

We will take reasonable measures which we believe are appropriate to protect your information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction, and, where possible, will ask that any third parties to whom we may transfer your information take comparable steps to protect that security. Although we will use all reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of any visitor information collected, we shall have no liability for disclosure of any visitor information obtained due to errors in transmission or the unauthorized acts of third parties. Email is not a secure form of communication. Please do not send us your credit card number, social security number or any other personal information via email.

## Links to Other Websites

We may offer links to other websites outside of our company. We make our best efforts to link with those websites that share the same values as we do. However, these websites should have their own privacy policies and in any event, are not governed by this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to read and review these third party privacy policies as we are not responsible for their content or information collection policies as they may treat their information differently.

## Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy

A note to parents:

We at Carma are committed to and strongly believe in the protection for children online. We want to encourage parents to spend some quality time with their children to review and monitor their online activity. We do not intend to collect any information from children under the age of 13 unless we have received a parent or guardian’s written permission. We may have links to children’s sites and if we would collect information from them on those sites we would do so in compliance with applicable children’s data protection laws. The U.S. websites that do collect information from children under the age of 13, are governed by a privacy statement meeting all of the requirements set forth by the U.S. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). Parents are able to review information the child has provided and can make any changes they feel are warranted, and at any time can inform us to remove their child’s information or make no further contact with the child.

[Click here](mailto:webmaster@carmalabs.com) to find out how you can obtain a copy of the information your child has provided Carma to update the information, or to have your child’s personal information removed.

## How to Contact Us

If you should have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please email us at lschneider@carma-labs.com. You may also reach us by telephone at 1-414-421-7707.

> **Mail:**  
>  Carma Laboratories, Inc.  
>  5801 West Airways Avenue  
>  Franklin, WI 53132
> 
> **Fax:**  
>  414-421-0737
> 
> **Email:**
